<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Terminal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just an Aussie with degrees in marine science, who, in my sparetime, loves self-hosting the various services I enjoy and depend on, with a specific focus on media-centric apps (i.e, the ‘Servarr-suite’ (Bazarr, Lidarr, Prowlarr, Radarr, Readarr, Sonarr and Whisparr)), which aid in my other favourite pastime of media consumption (when I&amp;rsquo;m not in War Thunder).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this blog will be to share various tidbits of information and guides from my experiences, especially those pertaining to my current ansible + docker swarm setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ansible-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ansible-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A weird thing I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed with my ansible journey are the number of people who either think that ansible is dying/dead. It simply is not so. Some of these &amp;lsquo;doomsayers&amp;rsquo; don&amp;rsquo;t approach ansible with a mindset of what can it do to help them achieve jobs and tasks, they approach it with whether learning it will give them the skill-set to fast-track their entry into a job, career, industry. These people will then jump onto Kubernetes and other solutions that are &amp;lsquo;all the rage&amp;rsquo; these days. But it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ansible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite tools in my homelab setup is ansible. I love it. Upon discovering it, my setup has changed rapidly after years of much stagnancy. For example:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2014-2020: I deployed containers on a Synology NAS (DS415+) and called it a day.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020-2023: I relied upon UnRaid&amp;rsquo;s community applications to deploy containers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During these years, things were working fine, and it is when I discovered the main applications I depend on, but I wanted more. In 2023, I installed the UnRaid Compose plug-in, and moved everything to Compose files, which culminated in me moving all my Compose files to a Debian VM on UnRaid. But there was still something missing. I still had to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-salty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-salty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When starting out with ansible, it&amp;rsquo;s common to begin with tutorials. Good places to start are those by Jeff Geerling, Learn Linux TV, tech-tubers like Techno Tim, Jim&amp;rsquo;s Garage, and a range of others. For me, these helped - but I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in simply getting hands on with ansible and taking a look at how others have approached their plays, tasks, roles, and then trying it out for yourself, adapting it for your needs, and building upon it. Whatever you&amp;rsquo;re setting out to do, chances are someones been down the same path. Ansible Galaxy is a good source for this, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.saltbox.dev/&#34;&gt;Saltbox&lt;/a&gt; most helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
